[
{
"question":"The reduction potential of hydrogen electrode will be positive if",
"choice1":"p(H2)=1atm,[H+]=1M",
"choice2":"p(H2)=1atm,[H+]=2M",
"choice3":"p(H2)=2atm,[H+]=1M",
"choice4":"p(H2)=2.5atm,[H+]=1.5M",
"Answer": 2
},
{
"question":"pure water does not conduct electricity because it is",
"choice1":"Neutral",
"choice2":"Readily decomposed",
"choice3":"Almost unionised",
"choice4":"Completely ionised",
"Answer": 3
},
{
"question":"The reactions taking place at anode and cathode of a cell respectively are",
"choice1":"Reduction, oxidation",
"choice2":"Oxidation, reduction",
"choice3":"Hydrolysis, oxidation",
"choice4":"Reduction, hydrolysis",
"Answer": 2
},
{
"question":"During electrolysis elections flow from",
"choice1":"cations to cathode",
"choice2":"anode to anions",
"choice3":"cathode to anode",
"choice4":"anions to anode",
"Answer": 4
},
{
"question":"Corrosion is",
"choice1":"Physical change",
"choice2":"Neutralisation",
"choice3":"Electrochemical change",
"choice4":"None is true",
"Answer": 3
},
{
"question":"VA group elements are known as",
"choice1":"Halogens",
"choice2":"Normal elements",
"choice3":"Chalcogens",
"choice4":"Pnicogens",
"Answer": 4
},
{
"question":"Which one of the following has the lowest melting point?",
"choice1":"N",
"choice2":"P",
"choice3":"As",
"choice4":"Sb",
"Answer": 1
},
{
"question":"The most thermodynamically stable allotropic form of phosphorus is",
"choice1":"Red P",
"choice2":"Yellow P",
"choice3":"Black P",
"choice4":"All are stable",
"Answer": 3
},
{
"question":"The VA group element having more number of allotropes is",
"choice1":"N",
"choice2":"P",
"choice3":"Bi",
"choice4":"Sb",
"Answer": 2
},
{
"question":"Basicity of orthophosphoric acid is",
"choice1":"2",
"choice2":"3",
"choice3":"4",
"choice4":"5",
"Answer": 2
},
{
"question":"Atomicity of white phosphorus is",
"choice1":"4",
"choice2":"3",
"choice3":"2",
"choice4":"8",
"Answer": 1
},
{
"question":"Bismuth forms the only pentahalide with the halogen",
"choice1":"Bromine",
"choice2":"Fluorine",
"choice3":"Chlorine",
"choice4":"Iodine",
"Answer": 2
},
{
"question":"Which of the following is tetrabasic acid",
"choice1":"Orthophosphotic acid",
"choice2":"Orthophosphorous acid",
"choice3":"Metaphosphoric acid",
"choice4":"Pyrophosphoric acid",
"Answer": 4
},
{
"question":"Bismuth forms the only pentahalide with the halogen",
"choice1":"Bromine",
"choice2":"Fluorine",
"choice3":"Chlorine",
"choice4":"Iodine",
"Answer": 2
},
{
"question":"Cyanamide process is used to prepare",
"choice1":"Cyanide",
"choice2":"Isocyanide",
"choice3":"Ammonia",
"choice4":"Nitric acid",
"Answer": 3
}

]